Guide to the Erving-King Family Papers 1709-1975 (bulk 1780-1939) MS 204
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: King and Related Families
  - Charles King Family, correspondence, 1815-1919 (Box 15, Folder K4)
    Inlcudes some photocopies
  - General Charles King, biographical notes, correspondence, photos, clippings, maps, 1876, 1899-1933 (Box 15, Folder K5)
  - Dr. Charles King, correspondence, 1868, 1888-1899 (Box 15, Folder K6)
  - Cyrus King Family, correspondence, 1709, 1811-1856, 1894-1898 (Box 16, Folder K7)
  - Cyrus King, correspondence, 1790-1817 (Box 16, Folder K8)
    Manuscript copies and typed copies
  - Edward King, biographical notes, correspondence, 1816-1828 (Box 16, Folder K9)
  - Edward King, biographical notes, school memorobilia, plan of house, stock certificate, obituaries, 1843-1909 (Box 16, Folder K10-A)
    Includes some manuscript copies, typed copies and photocopies
  - Edward King, school records and memorobilia - Harvard, 1850-1853, 1903-1908 (Box 16, Folder K10-B)
  - Edward King, correspondence sent to family, James Gore King and John Erving, 1847-1906 (Box 16, Folder K11)
  - Edward King, correspondence sent to Isabella R. Cochrane (Mrs. Edward King), 1857-1869 (Box 16, Folder K12)
  - Edward King, correspondence with friends and family, [1850-1901] (Box 16, Folder K13)
  - Edward King, business, professional, financial, 1862-1907 (Box 16, Folder K14)
  - Edward King, other writings, speeches, papers from Harvard, travel journals, 1847-1853 (Box 17, Folder K15-A)
  - Edward King, other writings, speeches - Harvard, Columbia, Yale, Princeton, Undated (Box 17, Folder K15-B)
    Includes typed copies
  - Edward King, legal and financial documents, receipts, passport, 1849-1908 (Box 17, Folder K16-A)
  - Edward King, copy of will, accounts of Executors, 1904, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder K16-B)
  - Edward King, accounts of Executors of will, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder K16-C)
  - Edward King, accounts of Executors of will, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder K16-D)
  - Edward King, accounts of Executors of will, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder K16-E)
  - Edward King, invitations, memberships, 1883-1893, 1902 (Box 18, Folder K17-A)
  - Edward King, invitations, 1894-1917 (Box 18, Folder K17-B)
  - Edward King, clippings and articles, 1888-1916, Undated (Box 18, Folder K18)
  - Edward King, descendants and relatives, 1899-1954 (Box 18, Folder K19)
  - Frederick Gore King, correspondence, and Harvard handbook, 1819-1826 (Box 19, Folder K20)
  - Isabella Cochrane King, correspondence, biographical and genealogical notes, 1864-1942 (Box 19, Folder K21-A)
  - Isabella Cochrane King, typescript of "A Woman's Whim" by Alice Clark (pseud.), Undated (Box 19, Folder K21-B)
  - Isabella Ramsey King, correspondence, 1850-1873 (Box 19, Folder K22-A)
  - Isabella Ramsey King, correspondence, 1857-1873 (Box 19, Folder K22-B)
  - James Gore King I, certificates of membership, 1817, 1829, 1845 (Box 19, Folder K23)
  - James Gore King I, biographical notes, clippings, articles, 1840-1958 (Box 19, Folder K24)
    Includes some manuscript copies and typed copies
  - James Gore King I, pamphlets- biographical and political, 1850-1854 (Box 19, Folder K25-A)
  - James Gore King I, Aid to Ireland, Report of the General Relief Committee of the City of New York, 1848 (Box 19, Folder K25-B)
  - James Gore King I, obituaries and memorials, 1853-1854 (Box 19, Folder K26)
  - James Gore King I, correpondence, 1813-1850 (Box 19, Folder K27)
  - James Gore King I, letterbook, 1826-1850 (Box 20, Folder K28)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence, 1838, 1850-1853 (Box 20, Folder K29)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence, 1808-1852 (Box 20, Folder K30-A)
    Manuscript copies, typed copies, photocopies
  - Correspondence with Harvard University and Public Archives of Canada regarding James Gore King I and the Baring Papers; notes on papers, 1931, 1968 (Box 20, Folder K30-B)
    Manuscript copies, typed copies
  - James Gore King I, correspondence with Baring Bros., 1827-1840 (Box 20, Folder K30-C)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence with Baring Bros., 1846-1852 (Box 20, Folder K30-D)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence with Baring Bros., 1840 (Box 21, Folder K30-E)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence with Baring Bros., 1847-1853 (Box 21, Folder K30-F)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence, 1839-1843 (Box 21, Folder K30-G)
  - James Gore King I, Commonplace book, 1814 (Box 21, Folder K31)
  - James Gore King I, legal financial documents, 1836-1852 (Box 21, Folder K32)
  - James Gore King I, documents and stock certificates- Prime, Ward and King; James B. King and Sons, 1839-1938 (Box 21, Folder K33)
  - James Gore King I, correspondence with wife, children, grandchildren, 1853-1878 (Box 21, Folder K34)
  - James Gore King II, correspondence, obituary, 1836-1857 (Box 21, Folder K35)
  - James Gore King IV, papers, 1868-1932 (Box 22, Folder K36)
  - James Gore King IV, obituaries and memorials, legal docuuments, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder K37)
  - James Gore King IV, correspondence, poems, 1885-1891 (Box 22, Folder K38)
  - James Gore King IV, correspondence, poems, 1883-1932 (Box 22, Folder K39-A)
  - James Gore King IV, correspondence, 1903-1932 (Box 22, Folder K39-B)
  - James Gore King IV, poems, 1916-1925, Undated (Box 22, Folder K39-C)
  - James Gore King IV, correspondence regarding Grace Church Cemetery Fund, 1907-1929 (Box 22, Folder K39-D)
  - James Gore King IV, St. Paul's Record, memorabilia from Harvard, 1881, 1888-1889 (Box 22, Folder K40-A)
  - James Gore King IV, memorabilia from Harvard, 1888-1910 (Box 22, Folder K40-B)
  - James Gore King IV, invitations, menus, programs, elections to organizations, 1894-1931 (Box 23, Folder K41)
  - James Gore King IV, clippings, 1864-1932 (Box 23, Folder K42)
  - Governor John A. King, biographical notes, correspondence, passports, 1826-1889, Undated (Box 23, Folder K43)
  - Governor John A. King, correspondence, 1816-1849 (Box 23, Folder K44-A)
    Photocopies and manuscript copies
  - Governor John A. King, correspondence, 1850-1867 (Box 23, Folder K44-B)
  - John A. King II, correspondence, speeches, memorial, 1842-1875 (Box 23, Folder K45)
  - Mrs. John A. (Mary Rhinelander) King, correspondence, 1827-1844 (Box 23, Folder K46)
  - Julia H. King, biographical information, school memorabilia, correspondence, 1902-1968 (Box 23, Folder K47)
  - Mrs. Mary Black (Richard) King, correspondence, excerpt from biographical manuscript by Dorcas King Leland, 1792, 1848 (Box 23, Folder K48)
    Includes typed copy
  - Mrs. May Denning (John) King Van Rensselaer, correspondence, clippings, 1897-1919 (Box 23, Folder K49)
  - Richard King (1718-1775), biographical notes, correspondence relating to memorial, 1901-1931 (Box 23, Folder K50)
  - Rufus King, biographical notes and research, will, original and manuscript copy, 1825, 1894-1921, Undated (Box 24, Folder K51)
  - Rufus King, correspondence, copper plate for calling card, 1776-1823 (Box 24, Folder K52)
  - Rufus King, domestic letterbook, 1799-1803 (Box 24, Folder K53)
    1 volume
  - Rufus King, receipts, calling cards, journal, 1791-1796, 1826-1827 (Box 24, Folder K54-A)
  - Rufus King
    - Rufus King, government documents, draft letters, resolutions regarding Grace Church, 1794-1822 (Box 24, Folder K54-B)
    - The Traveller's Directory...from Philadelphia to New York...., 1804 (Box 24, Folder K54-B)
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence in possession of James Gore King IV, 1785-1826 (Box 25, Folder K54-C)
    Typed copies, 1 volume
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence on file at the State Department, 1796-1798 (Box 25, Folder K54-D)
    Manuscript copies, 1 volume
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence, 1784-1825 (Box 25, Folder K54-E)
    Manuscript, typed and photocopies
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence from and concerning his sons, Charles King and John Alsop King, 1799-1803 (Box 25, Folder K54-F)
    Typed copies
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence, 1786-1826 (Box 25, Folder K54-G)
  - Rufus King, list and copies of correspondence, 1785-1826 (Box 25, Folder K54-H)
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence, excerpt from diary, 1775-1803 (Box 26, Folder K54-I)
  - Rufus King, copies of correspondence, biographical and research notes, 1755-1815, Undated (Box 26, Folder K54-J)
  - Rufus King, early pamphlets and speeches, 1818-1823 (Box 26, Folder K55)
  - General Rufus King, correspondence, biographical notes, obituary, 1838-1876 (Box 26, Folder K56)
    Includes some manuscript copies and photocopies
  - General Rufus King, invitations, menus, calling cards, 1864-1867 (Box 26, Folder K57)
  - Rufus King III, biographical notes, Undated (Box 26, Folder K58)
  - Sarah Erving King, correspondence, clippings, invitations, picture, will, obituaries, 1928-1955, Undated (Box 26, Folder K59)
  - Sarah Erving King, correspondence, memo book, 1924-1939, Undated (Box 27, Folder K60-A)
  - Sarah Erving King, account book, 1946-1955 (Box 27, Folder K60-B)
  - Governor William King, biographical notes and research, correpondence, 1804-1852, 1927, 1954, Undated (Box 27, Folder K61)
    Includes some typed copies and photocopies
  - Alsop and Underhill Families, genealogical notes, correspondence, clippings, 1776, 1880-1931, Undated (Box 27, Folder K62)
  - Alsop Family, correspondence, 1766-1794 (Box 27, Folder K63)
  - Ames and Marsh Families, genealogical notes, correspondence, clippings, photographs, 1918-1959, Undated (Box 27, Folder K64)
  - Bragdon Family, genealogical notes, correspondence, 1902-1923, Undated (Box 27, Folder K65)
  - Clarke and Williamson, correspondence sent to Isabella King, clippings, photographs, 1907-1917 (Box 27, Folder K66)
  - Cochrane Family, biographical notes, correspondence, 1836-1913, Undated (Box 28, Folder K67-A)
  - Cochrane Family, correspondence, 1860-1931 (Box 28, Folder K67-B)
  - Bayard Cochrane, military papers, expense accounts, 1857-1864 (Box 28, Folder K68-A)
  - Bayard Cochrane, correspondence, 1858-1864 (Box 28, Folder K68-B)
  - Bayard Cochrane, scrapbook with photographs and correspondence, 1858-1864, Undated (Box 28, Folder K69)
  - Rupert J. and Isabella M. Cochrane, legal documents, correspondence, 1850-1860, Undated (Box 28, Folder K70-A)
  - Rupert Cochrane, correspondence from Crimea (Sebastopol), 1854-1855 (Box 28, Folder K70-B)
  - Rupert Cochrane, correspondence from Crimea, India, 1856-1859 (Box 28, Folder K70-C)
  - Rupert Cochrane, correspondence from India, 1860-1864 (Box 29, Folder K70-D)
  - Rupert Cochrane, military papers, 1859-1863 (Box 29, Folder K70-E)
  - William G. Cochrane, correspondence, 1861-1865 (Box 29, Folder K70-F)
  - William G. Cochrane, correspondence, 1865-1869 (Box 29, Folder K70-G)
  - Frederica (King) Davis, correspondence with relatives, will, memorabilia, 1852-1916 (Box 29, Folder K71)
  - Duer Family, biographical notes, correspondence, clippings, 1827-1949 (Box 29, Folder K72)
  - Christopher Gore, correspondence, notes regarding gift of books to Harvard, 1799-1802 (Box 29, Folder K73)
    Includes some photocopies, typed copies. Some originals in Folder K53.
  - Gracie Family, correspondence, biographical notes, 1891-1930 (Box 29, Folder K74-A)
    Includes some photocopies, typed copies.
  - Gracie Family, correspondence, clippings regarding Gracie Mansion, 1793-1930 (Box 29, Folder K74-B)
    Photocopies, typed copies of correpondence.
  - Hardy Family, correspondence, notes, [1941]-1945, undated (Box 30, Folder K75)
  - Hurley Family, correspondence, genealogical notes, clippings, will, 1908-1957, undated (Box 30, Folder K76-A)
  - Inglis, Davidson, Musgrave Families, correspondence, receipts, 1857-1861, Undated (Box 30, Folder K76-B)
  - Stewart-Richardson Family, correspondence, clippings, 1909-1962, Undated (Box 30, Folder K77-A)
  - Alice Stewart-Richardson, correspondence, 1861-1919 (Box 30, Folder K77-B)
  - Fanny (King) [Mrs. Edmund] Ward, correspondence, 1867-1892, Undated (Box 30, Folder K78)
  - Fanny (King) [Mrs. Edmund] Ward, correspondence, 1869 Nov.-1870 July (Box 30, Folder K79)
  - Fanny (King) [Mrs. Edmund] Ward, correspondence, 1870 Aug.-1870 Dec. (Box 30, Folder K80)
  - Fanny (King) [Mrs. Edmund] Ward, correspondence, 1871 Jan.-1871 June (Box 30, Folder K81)
  - Dr. George Wilkes, correspondence with family, 1826 (Box 30, Folder K82-A)
  - Dr. George Wilkes, correspondence with family, 1827 (Box 30, Folder K82-B)
  - Dr. George Wilkes, diary, account book, 1827 Jan.-1827 June (Box 30, Folder K83)
  - Dr. George Wilkes, correspondence with family, [1837], 1852-1863 (Box 31, Folder K84)
  - Dr. George Wilkes Family, genealogical notes, correspondence, [1805]-1855, Undated (Box 31, Folder K85-A)
  - Grace Wilkes, invitations, valentines, auction catalogs, clippings, 1849-1860, 1922-1923, 1952, Undated (Box 31, Folder K85-B)
  - Grace Wilkes, will, 1921 (Box 31, Folder K85-C)
  - Grace Wilkes, European Journal, copies of correspondence from Charles Dickens to David and Frances (Wilkes) Colden, [1840-1859] (Box 31, Folder K86-A)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, [1850-1869] (Box 32, Folder K86-B)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, [1840]-1883 (Box 32, Folder K86-C)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, [1850-1859] (Box 32, Folder K86-D)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence envelopes, [1850-1859] (Box 32, Folder K86-E)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, 1855-1856 (Box 32, Folder K86-F)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, invitations, [1850-1859] (Box 32, Folder K86-G)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, calling cards, 1854-1858, Undated (Box 32, Folder K86-H)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, 1850 (Box 32, Folder K86-I)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, 1851 (Box 32, Folder K86-J)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, [1850-1859], 1884, 1913, Undated (Box 33, Folder K86-K)
  - Grace and Harriet Wilkes, correspondence, [1849-1859] (Box 33, Folder K86-L)
  - Hamilton Wilkes, Lord Jeffrey and others, correspondence, court documents, 1840-1843 (Box 33, Folder K86-M)
  - Wilkes and Related Families, correspondence, notes, 1772-1856, Undated (Box 33, Folder K86-N)
  - David C. and Harriet (Wilkes) Colden, correspondence, legal papers, 1817-1847 (Box 33, Folder K86-O)
  - David C. and Harriet (Wilkes) Colden, correspondence, legal and financial, 1803-1848 (Box 33, Folder K86-P)
  - David C. and Harriet (Wilkes) Colden, diary, 1859-1866 (Box 33, Folder K86-P)
  - King and Related Families, legal documents, 1793-1839 (Box 34, Folder K87)
  - King and Related Families, legal documents regarding Highwood, 1840-1849 (Box 34, Folder K88-A)
  - King and Related Families, legal documents regarding Highwood, 1850-1853 (Box 34, Folder K88-B)
  - King and Related Families, legal and financial documents regarding Highwood, 1855-1903 (Box 34, Folder K89-A)
  - King and Related Families, legal and financial documents regarding Highwood, 1845-1903 (Box 34, Folder K89-B)
  - King and Related Families, legal documents regarding Grace Church and Cemetery, Jamaica, NY, 1908-1912, 1954-1956, Undated (Box 35, Folder K90)
  - King and Related Families, legal documents regarding Grace Church and Cemetary, Jamaica, NY, 1897-1898, 1910, 1954 (Box 35, Folder K91)
  - King and Related Families, inventories, appraisals, acknowledgements of gifts, 1923-1949 (Box 35, Folder K92)
  - King and Related Families, inventories, correspondence regarding family portraits, 1911-1954, Undated (Box 35, Folder K93)
    Includes some photocopies, typed copies
  - King and Related Families, legal and personal documents, U.S. Revenue Stamps, [1845-1891] (Box 35, Folder K94)
  - King and Related Families, memorabilia, 1844-1960, Undated (Box 35, Folder K95)
  - King and Related Families, sketchbook (probably Bayard Cochrane), [1858] (Box 35, Folder K96)
  - King and Related Families, correspondence, some unidentified, 1831-1934, Undated (Box 35, Folder K97)
  - King and Related Families, notebook: "Considerations on the Colonies", Undated (Box 35, Folder K98)
  - King and Related Families, writings, Undated (Box 35, Folder K99)
  - Wheeler H. Peckham (not related), correspondence, receipts, obituaries, clippings, 1878-1905 (Box 35, Folder K100)
  - King Family, correspondence, includes Eleanor Roosevelt's signature, 1819-1945, Undated (Box 36, Folder K101)
  - King Family, prints, drawings, paintings, 1803-1804, 1830, 1941, Undated (Box 36, Folder K102)
  - King Family, pamphlets, 1855-1940, Undated (Box 36, Folder K103)
  - King Family, clippings, 1911-1970, Undated (Box 36, Folder K104-A)
  - King Family, clippings, 1851-1927, Undated (Box 36, Folder K104-B)
  - King Family, maps - United States; Mount Desert Island, ME; England and Wales, 1834, 1901, Undated (Box 36, Folder K105)
  - King Family, Christening Stock worn by James G. King I and III, [1789] (Box 36, Folder K106-A)
  - King Family, correspondence primarily from literary and publishing figures, 1764, 1847-1936, Undated (Box 36, Folder K106-B)
  - King Family, correspondence unrelated to family, probably purchased from Walter Benjamin, 1788-1922, Undated (Box 36, Folder K106-C)
  - "The Record of my Ancestry" Traced by Isabella Clarke King, 1897 (Volume K1)
  - Bayard Cochrane, textbook, Fortification Notes. R.M.A., Undated (Volume K2)
  - Edward King, scrapbook with clippings, Undated (Volume K3)
  - Letterbook, 1774-1862 (Volume K4)
    Disbound; includes some photocopies
  - Letterbook, 1791-1894 (Volume K5)
    Disbound
  - Rufus A. King, Album, manuscript translations of the Lord's Prayer in many languages, 1866 (Volume K8)
  - James Gore King IV, scrapbook, 1881-1889 (Volume K9)
  - James Gore King IV, scrapbook, Harvard, 1886-1889 (Volume K10)
  - James Gore King IV, scrapbook, Harvard, 1889-1892 (Volume K11)
  - King Family of Salem, MA. and Southold, N.Y., scrapbook and Pedigree, [1871-1889] (Volume K12)
- Series III: Oversize Materiels
  Consists of maps, genealogical charts, drawings, broadsides and certificates relating to the Erving and King Families.
  - Subseries I: Maps
    - "Key Map" King property in N.J., Undated (Folder 1)
    - Orange, MA, 1871 (Folder 1)
    - Erving, MA and Wendell, MA, 1871 (Folder 1)
    - Bath, England, Undated (Folder 1)
    - Schematic map, Highwood, drawn by Rufus King, 1837 Jan. (Folder 1)
    - Plot no. 5 from map of Highwood, 1846 (Folder 1)
    - Survey, 188 lots, Union, N.J., Undated (Folder 1)
    - Sound View Park, Rye, N.Y., 1892 (Folder 1)
    - Plan of City of New York, from original, 1789 (Folder 1)
    - Map of property owned by A. Gracie King and others, Putnam, County, N.Y., 1912 (Folder 1)
    - Portland, ME. Quadrangle, United States Geological Survey, reprinted, 1932 (Folder 1)
  - Subseries II: Genealogical Charts
    - Ancestors of James Gore King (1868-1932) m. Sarah Elizabeth Erving (1870-1955), Undated (Folder 2)
    - Ancestors of Sarah Elizabeth Erving and her 11 siblings, Undated (Folder 2)
    - Ancenstors of 5 sons of Rufus and Mary (Alsop) King, Undated (Folder 2)
    - Photocopy Chart 2, Undated (Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of Van Rensselaer family charts, 3 sections: Ancestors of Kiliaen and Hendrick Van Rensselaer in Holland; Descendents of Kiliaen Van Rensselaer (1663-1719); Decendents of Hendrick Van Rensselaer (1667-1740), Undated (Folder 2)
    - Interrelationships of United States Presidents, Undated (Folder 2)
  - Subseries III: Drawings, Broadsides, Certificates, etc.
    - Van Rensselaer Manor House, Watervliet (Albany), N.Y., handdrawn and colored, [1868] (Folder 3)
    - Unidentified fort, handdrawn and colored, property of Col. John Erving, Undated (Folder 3)
    - Battle of Cerro Gordo, 1847, drawn by Capt. McCleean, property of Col. John Erving, Undated (Folder 3)
    - Fowler's New Map of the Hudson River, 1845 (Folder 3)
    - C.D. Colden Election Broadside, Undated (Folder 3)
    - Broadsides, certificates, Undated (Folder 3)
    - Exemplification of the letters of administration (with the will annexed) of John Erving, deceased, 1816 (Folder 3)